Qurban Ahmad

Full Stack Developer

6204789892 | ahmad76qurban@gmail.com | Chaibasa, Jharkhand, India

https://linkedin.com/in/qurban-ahmad-qur786/ | portfolio | Github

Summary

Experienced Full Stack Developer with 2.5+ years in React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, and AWS. Proficient in Node, Express.js, MongoDB, AWS DynamoDB, tools (Babel, Webpack, NPM, Yarn), and Git. Strong in translating business requirements into technical solutions.

Skills

MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js, Redux, Next.js, Java, React Native, HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Typescript, Material UI, Mantine UI, D3.js, ECharts.js, GraphQL, REST API, Socket.io, AWS, Web Development, Mobile Development, PWA Development, Electron, SQL, Jest, Playwright, C, C++, Webpack, Babel, Git, Linux, Docker, ESLint, Storybook.js

Professional Experience

Software Development Engineer 1 (SDE 1)

2023-04-01-2023-09-30

Manufac Analytics Pvt Ltd, Gurugram

- Engineered diverse projects including single and multi-page React applications, web applications, and cross-platform Electron apps.
- Revamped the company's SaaS product code with AWS and Mantine UI, resulting in a notable 20% boost in system functionality and a 25% reduction in code management effort.
- Added rigorous Jest and Playwright testing.
- Guided and helped team members to enhance coding practices.

Front End Developer

2022-01-26-2023-03-31

Manufac Analytics Pvt Ltd, Gurugram

- Created mobile-responsive components, charts, and forms in React and various libraries such as Formik, D3.js, ECharts, ReactTable, and MUI.
- Achieved a 90%+ score in Lighthouse by optimizing website performance.
- Notable innovations include user activity tracker desktop app, Bluetooth device data reading via Web API, and real-time IoT tracking of devices with AWS IoT, Geofencing, Lambda, and SNS.

Front End Developer Intern

 $2021\hbox{-}07\hbox{-}27\hbox{-}\ 2022\hbox{-}01\hbox{-}26$

Manufac Analytics Pvt Ltd, Gurugram

- Added charts and UI components to the company's core app, resulting in 5% newly added functionality.
- Collaborated effectively on the integration of the PayPal payment API into the company's web app.
- Integrated API to the company's core app.

Web Developer Intern

 $2021\hbox{-}02\hbox{-}19\hbox{-}\ 2021\hbox{-}04\hbox{-}10$

Adityapur Auto Cluster, Jamshedpur

- Analyzed issues and led the development of a storage management web app in PHP, delivering an impressive 20% boost in productivity over the previous system.
- Designed and developed the backend of the app, and added 60% of the backend code.

Education

Bachelor of Science (BSc) - Information Technology

2018-08-01-2021-11-20

Mrs. KMPM Vocational College, Jamshedpur

87.21%